Finding Aid for Office of Human Resources and Affirmative Action (University of Michigan) Records, 1964-2004
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Affirmative Action
  - Women
    - CEW (Continuing Education for Women/Center for the Education of Women)
      - General, 1972-1988 (Box 10)
      - Non-Traditional Student Attitudes and Needs, 1982 (Box 10)
    - Child Care
      - General, 1970-1984; 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Minutes, 1983-1984 (Box 10)
      - Surveys, 1973-1979 (Box 10)
    - Citizen's Advisory Committee on Rape Prevention
      - 1983-1986, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Commission for Women
      - Career Guides, 1985-1986 (Box 10)
      - General
        - 1975-1991, 2 folders (Box 10)
        - 1997-1998, 4 folders (Box 10)
      - Minutes and Agendas, 1980-1988 (Box 10)
    - Committee on the Status of Women in Graduate Education, 1973-1977 (Box 11)
    - Discrimination Policies Implementation Team, 1988; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Equal Rights Amendment, 1981 (Box 11)
    - Every Women's Guide to Colleges and Universities, 1981-1983 (Box 11)
    - Internships, 1980-1991 (Box 11)
    - Legislation concerning Women, 1973 (Box 11)
    - Miscellanea, 1972-1977 (Box 11)
    - National Organization for Women, 1978-1983 (Box 11)
    - News Articles, 1972-1986 (Box 11)
    - Pamphlets, 1980; undated (Box 11)
    - Public Forum on the Future of Women at the University of Michigan, 1988 (Box 11)
    - Radio Proposal for "Women Now", 1981 (Box 11)
    - Rape, 1980-1983 (Box 11)
    - Women's Information Fair, 1971 (Box 11)
    - Women's Information Group (WING)
      - Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 11)
      - General, 1983-1987; 2 folders (Box 11)
      - Meeting Schedules and Minutes, 1988-1989; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Women's Organizations Resource List, 1986-1987 (Box 11)
    - Women's Weekend--Residential College
      - 1985 (Box 11)
      - 1986 (Box 11)
- Personnel
  The Personnel records (8.6 linear feet), covering the period from 1972 to 2001, are divided into two series: Schools and Colleges and Compensation Manuals and Programs.
  - Colleges and Schools
    The Schools and Colleges series (6 linear feet) (1974-2000) documents specific questions regarding pay, promotions, reductions in service, medical, personal, and sabbatical leaves, gender, age, and racial discrimination, and sexual and racial harassment for the faculty and staff of the university from 1974 to 1999. For this reason, these records are restricted for thirty (30) years after creation. They are arranged alphabetically for the individual school and college. The general folders contain information about searches and sensitive issues such as harassment and discipline of individual employees. The faculty and staff folders also relate to individual university employees usually relating to hiring, promotions, and discrimination.
    - Architecture and Urban Planning, College of
      - General, 1974-1997 (Box 12)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2027 ]
      - Organization and Staff Planning Review, 1995 (Box 12)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2025 ]
      - Faculty and Staff A-Z, 1987-1998 (Box 12)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2028 ]
    - Art and Design, School of
      - General, 1984-1998 (Box 12)
      - Staff A-Z, 1989-1998 (Box 12)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1; 2028 ]
    - Business Administration, School of
      - General, 1988-2000 (Box 12)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2030 ]
      - Faculty and Staff A-Z, 1990-2001; 3 folders (Box 12)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2031 ]
    - Dearborn, University of Michigan
      - General, 1986-1998 (Box 12)
      - Faculty and Staff A-Z, 1985-1999; 2 folders (Box 12)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2029 ]
    - Dentistry, School of
      - General, 1987-1998 (Box 12)
      - Faculty and Staff A-Z, 1989-1997; 4 folders (Box 12)
    - Education, School of (Box 13)
      - General, 1985-1998 (Box 13)
      - Faculty and Staff A-Z, 1990-1998; 4 folders (Box 13)
    - Engineering, College of
      - General, 1983-1998 (Box 13)
      - Faculty and Staff A-Z, 1990-1999; 5 folders (Box 13)
    - Flint, University of Michigan
      - Correspondence, 1986-1999; 2 folders (Box 13)
      - Fact Book, 1992/93 (Box 13)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2023 ]
      - Faculty, 1989 (Box 13)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2019 ]
      - Faculty and Staff A-Z, 1986-1998; 5 folders (Box 13)
      - Faculty Petition, 1992 (Box 13)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2022 ]
    - Graduate School, Horace H. Rackham
      - General, 1987-1996 (Box 13)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2026 ]
      - Faculty and Staff A-Z, 1986-1999 (Box 13)
    - Information and Library Studies, School of (Box 14)
      - General, 1991-1997 (Box 14)
      - Faculty and Staff A-Z, 1989-1999 (Box 14)
    - Kinesiology, includes Division of Physical Education
      - General, 1984-1987 (Box 14)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2017 ]
      - Faculty and Staff A-Z, 1984-1999; 4 folders (Box 14)
    - Law School
      - General, 1976-1999 (Box 14)
      - Faculty and Staff, 1987-1999; 2 folders (Box 14)
    - LSA (College of Literature, Science, and the Arts)
      - General, 1986-1999 (Box 14)
      - Faculty and Staff A-Z, 1989-1999; 8 folders (Box 14)
      - Individual Faculty, 1990-1993; 7 folders (Box 15)
      - Key Administrator Steering Committee, 1994 (Box 15)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2024 ]
      - Lecturers, 1991-1992 (Box 15)
    - Medical School
      - General, 1986-1998; 4 folders (Box 15)
      - Faculty and Staff A-Z, 1988-1999; 4 folders (Box 15)
      - Clinical Track Promotions, 1991 (Box 16)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2021 ]
      - Departments
        - Otolaryngology Diversity Committee, 1991; 1994; 2 folders (Box 16)
        - Pathology Annual Report, 1989/90 (Box 16)
          [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2020 ]
      - Faculty Career Development Task Force, 1991-1992; 2 folders (Box 16)
      - Individual Faculty, 1989-1993; 5 folders (Box 16)
      - Limited Term Assistant Professors, 1991-1992 (Box 16)
      - Salary Structure, 1979-1991 (Box 16)
      - Women Faculty, 1990 (Box 16)
    - Music, School of
      - General, 1988-1997 (Box 16)
      - Faculty and Staff A-Z, 1989-1999; 2 folders (Box 16)
    - Natural Resources and Environment, School of
      - General, 1988-1997 (Box 16)
      - Faculty and Staff A-Z, 1986-1996 (Box 16)
      - Searches, 1995 (Box 16)
    - Nursing, School of
      - General 1986-1997 Faculty and Staff A-Z, 1988-1999 (Box 16)
      - Nurse Recruitment Plan Analysis, 1990 (Box 16)
    - Pharmacy, College of
      - General, 1988-1997 (Box 16)
      - Faculty and Staff A-Z, 1988-1998 (Box 16)
    - Public Health, School of
      - General, 1974-1997 (Box 17)
      - Faculty and Staff A-Z, 1987-1999 (Box 17)
      - Individual Faculty, 1992-1994; 2 folders (Box 17)
      - Organization Assessment, 1995 (Box 17)
    - Public Policy, School of (includes Institute of Public Policy)
      - General, 1992-1997; 2 folders (Box 17)
      - Faculty and Staff A-Z, 1981-1998; 2 folders (Box 17)
      - Public Service Database, 1993 (Box 17)
    - Social Work, School of
      - General, 1971-1997 (Box 17)
      - Faculty and Staff A-Z, 1984-1997 (Box 17)
    - Other University Units (Box 17)
    - University Library
      - General, 1994-1997 (Box 17)
  - Compensation Manuals
    The Compensation Manuals and Programs series (2.6 linear feet) (1972-1996) covers the period from 1971 to 1996 and includes compensation schedules, an alphabetical and numerical list of all university job classifications, and a alphabetical and numerical listing of the job departments. There are similar lists for temporary positions within the university. In 1974 they also broke out occupation groups. The merit salary incentive data was added to the notebooks in 1980. The Compensation Programs notebook covers the years from 1976 to 1988. It includes compensation changes by job family, average salaries by grade, salary schedules by grade and family, and compensation adjustments for both permanent and temporary employees. There are also classification descriptions and qualifications for temporary hires. In 1981-1982 there is a detailed description of the merit salary increase program.
    - 1971-1982, 10 volumes (Box 18)
    - 1982-1991, 9 volumes (Box 19)
    - 1991-1993, 2 folders (Box 20)
    - 1994-1996, 2 folders (Box 20)
    - Compensation Programs (Box 20)
    - 1976-1992 (Box 20)
- Human Resources and Affirmative Action
  The Human Resources and Affirmative Action records include video tapes and DVD recordings (.8 linear feet) of the annual service awards presentation administered by the Office of Human Resources and Affirmative Action. These VHS tapes and DVD recordings document the period from 1995 to 2004. They contain photographs of employees who have served the university for at least thirty years and more in increments of five years. Included with each video, from 1996 to the present, are printed programs listing those who have worked at the university for twenty years and more. There is also an undated VHS tape entitled 20 Years is...Celebrating Twenty Years of Service at the University of Michigan.
  - Audio-Visual Material
    - Service Award Video Tapes (VHS)
      - 20 Years is...Celebrating Twenty Years of Service at the University of Michigan, undated (Box 20)
      - 1995 (Box 20)
      - Includes Programs, 1996-1998; 3 folders (Box 20)
      - Includes Programs, 1999-2003; 5 folders (Box 21)
    - Service Award DVD, DVD
      - Includes Programs, 2004 (Box 21)
Related Material
Researchers should also consult the records and publications finding aids of:
University of Michigan. Personnel Office
University of Michigan. Affirmative Action Office
In compliance with the Michigan Freedom of Information Act, the Personnel Office published the salary information for all university employees. These publications will be found in the University of Michigan. Office of Human Resources and Affirmative Action publications.